Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Website: <u>amlan-banaji.github.io</u>

Email: A.F.Banaji "at" lboro.ac.uk

Research Associate in Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University's mathematics department since March 2023

Nationality: UK

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My main research interests are in geometry and analysis related to fractal sets and measures. These 'fractals' exhibit complexity over a wide range of scales, and often arise in a natural dynamical way, such as via (conformal or nonconformal) iterated function systems. Currently, I am especially interested in the rate of decay of the Fourier transform of stationary measures for such systems. I have also done a lot of work exploring different ways one can define 'dimension,' to provide refined information about the global or local scaling properties of classes of sets or measures. I enjoy finding connections between these topics and other areas of mathematics such as number theory and probability theory.

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

Preprints:

- 10. S. Baker and A. Banaji. Polynomial Fourier decay for fractal measures and their pushforwards. arXiv
- 9. A. Banaji, J. M. Fraser, I. Kolossváry and A. Rutar. Assouad spectrum of Gatzouras—Lalley carpets. arXiv
- 8. A. Banaji, A. Rutar and S. Troscheit. *Interpolating with generalized Assouad dimensions*, Submitted. arXiv
- 7. A. Banaji and I. Kolossváry. *Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to* Lipschitz equivalence, Submitted to Advances in Mathematics. arXiv

Published:

- 6. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets Nonlinearity 37 (2024), 045004. arXiv
- 5. A. Banaji. Generalised intermediate dimensions Monatshefte für Mathematik 202 (2023), 465–506. arXiv
- 4. A. Banaji. *Metric spaces where geodesics are never unique* American Mathematical Monthly 130 (2023), 747–754. arXiv
- 3. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors* Transactions of the American Mathematical Society 376 (2023), 2449–2479. arXiv
- 2. A. Banaji and H. Chen. Dimensions of popcorn-like pyramid sets Journal of Fractal Geometry 10 (2023), 151–169. arXiv
- 1. A. Banaji and A. Rutar. Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions Annales Fennici Mathematici 47 (2022), 939–960. arXiv

EDUCATION

University of St Andrews

PhD Mathematics

2019-2023

Thesis: "Interpolating between Hausdorff and box dimension" (defended May 2023)

With the Analysis Research Group

Topic: Fractal geometry and dimension theory

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the Leverhulme Trust

University of St Andrews

2018-2019

MSc Mathematics, Distinction

GPA: 19.5/20. Ranked 1st in the Faculty of Science and Medicine Dissertation:

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015–2018

BA (Hons) Mathematics

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

PRIZES AND GRANTS

- 2023–4: Awarded £500 LMS Travel Grant for Early Career Researchers to visit the University of Oulu
- 2019: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best MSc student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

TALKS

I have given at least 35 talks (see https://amlan-banaji.github.io/files/BanajiTalks.pdf) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Topology and Dynamics Seminar (Birmingham, 8/2/24)
- Geometric Analysis Seminar (Jyväskylä, 1/2/24)
- <u>Analysis Seminar</u> (Oulu, 26/1/24)
- Fractal Geometry (celebrating Prof. Kenneth Falconer's 70th birthday, ICMS, Edinburgh, 4/7/23)
- Multifractal analysis and self-similarity (CIRM, Marseille, 30/6/23)
- <u>Diophantine Approximation, Dynamics, and Fractals</u> (Exeter, 22/6/23)
- Thermodynamic Formalism: Non-additive Aspects and Related Topics (Bedlewo, 16/5/23)
- Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems Seminar (Bristol, 13/3/23)
- Analysis Seminar (Edinburgh, 13/3/23)
- One World Fractals (online, 18/1/23)
- Szenzhen Technology University Mathematics Colloquium (China (online), inaugural talk, 22/10/22)
- <u>Fractals and Related Fields IV</u> (Porquerolles, France, 5/9/22)
- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, 30/6/22)
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, 11/5/22)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, 22/3/23, 3/5/22, 12/10/21, 20/4/21, 30/6/20)

EXPERIENCE

- March-May 2024: will **lecture** half of second-year course "Elements of Topology" at Loughborough
- Teaching undergraduate **tutorials** at the University of St Andrews:

Most recent student feedback score: 1.5 on a scale from 1 to 5 (where 1 is highest).

2019–2022: MT2502 Analysis (10 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- 2018–2022: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with G5 Education, Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.

SERVICE

- 2023–4: Co-organiser of Workshop on Ergodic Theory and Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University
- 2023–present: **Co-organiser** of the <u>Loughborough University Dynamical Systems Seminar</u>
- 2022—present: **Referee** for Adv. Math. and Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A and Colloq. Math. and Amer. Math. Monthly and J. Math. Anal. Appl. and Real Anal. Exchange and MathSciNet
- 2022: **Organiser** of St Andrews Analysis Reading Group
- 2021: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES

London Mathematical Society, Edinburgh Mathematical Society, Institute of Mathematics and its Applications